麥特坎姆先生
Chief Metacomet.
沒有您父親的幫忙
Without
我們誰也活不過第一個冬天.
your father's friendship, none of us could have survived.
我父親應該讓你們
My father should have let you
去死!
die!
你是
You are
唯一
the only one
帶著坦誠之心
who comes to us
來找我們的人.
with an open heart.
可你的人用謊言
But your people have murdered
謀殺了
my father
我的父親!
with their lies!
我叫珠兒.
My name is Pearl.
這個故事是關於我的母親, 海絲特·白蘭因.
This is the story of my mother, Hester Prynne.
那是在1666年,
It was the year of our Lord 1666,
當她到達了馬賽諸賽海岸殖民地
when she arrived in the Massachusetts Bay Colony
滿心希望在這裏，在這個新世界裏
filled with the hope that at last, in this new world
能夠最終自由的信仰，而沒有恐懼和迫害
would come the freedom to worship without fear of persecution.
我尊敬的同僚!
My esteemed colleague!
多年的辛苦讓你更健康了!
Thy years of toil become thee!
久仰您的大名，先生.
Thy fame preceeds thee, sir.
貝靈漢總督,
Governor Bellingham,
允許我介紹
may I present
托馬斯·奇夫牧師.
the Reverend Thomas Cheever.
歡迎您先生. 一路辛苦了.
Welcome, sir. It's a long voyage.
海上三個月,
3 months at sea,
要麼奪走你的信仰, 要麼使它堅硬如鐵.
will either take away your faith, or harden it to iron.
貝靈漢總督 允許我向您介紹一位與我們同行的女士
Allow me to introduce a woman who's been travelling with us,
海絲特·白蘭因夫人
- Mistress... - Hester Prynne.
請原諒我這雙
I apologize for the coarseness
粗糙的手, 夫人.
of my hands, Mistress.
不過這裏是殖民地, 誰都得幹活.
But here in the colonies, everyone must work.
我渴望繁重的工作,總督.
I look forward to the hard work.
就像《舊約》92篇中所寫的: "我將靠自己的雙手 取得勝利".
It says id Psalm 92: "I will triumph in the work of thy hands".
沒想道您會引用聖經.
Thou canst quote the Scriptures.
是的，牧師，舊約和新約 我丈夫教我的
Aye, Reverendo, both Testaments. My husband taught me.
您得休息了，奇夫牧師.
You must rest.
然後，我很願意帶您參觀我們的成就
Then I'll show you what's been accomplished.
非常感謝.
I thank thee.
- 哦，這是白蘭因太太. - 是的，是的.
- Then it's Goodwife Prynne. - Yes, yes.
不過我更喜歡別人叫我海絲特.
But I prefer to be called Hester.
歡迎你, 海絲特.
Welcome, Hester.
要是能跟著第一批來這兒多好,
I wish I could've seen it before,
當時還是原始的荒蠻之地
when it was wild and untouched.
太太,
Madam,
在這個地方 少掛點裝飾會更好.
you should use less lace in your dressmaking.
當然, 牧師.
Indeed, Reverend.
全能的上帝啊,
Master of us all,
感謝您再次慷慨地賜予我們食物
we give thanks for another bountiful meal,
感謝這些新到達的信徒,
and for newly arrived disciples,
與我們分享此宴.
that share it with us this night.
- 阿門. - 阿門.
- Amen. - Amen.
總督先生.
So, Governor.
我迫不及待地想知道 你和麥特坎姆談判的情況.
I am impatient to know how you fared with Metacomet.
哦，麥特坎姆不是瑪薩索米，鄧姆上校.
Well, Metacomet isn't Massassoit, Major Dunsmuir.
但我相信如果我們遵守與他父親之間的協議
But if we respect the agreements we made with his father,
就沒什麼可怕的
we've nothing to fear.
英名的上帝怕我們
So we don't grow complacent,
得意忘形
our wise God sends us a sign.
所以下了神諭
When we sailed,
總督先生，我們在信上看到你說我們與野人和平相處.
your letters said we were at peace with the savage.
哦,
Well,
跟帕諾亞人所謂的和平日子就要到頭了
I fear the days of "peace" with the Wampanoag is at an end.
少校,
Major,
我們嚇著這些新來的人了
we are frightening our new arrival.
我在家常聽說你們
We hear much
讓印第安人皈依我主
of your success with the praying Indians.
我非常渴望拜見丁梅斯黛爾牧師
I'm very eager to meet Reverend Dimmesdale
和他的皈依者
and his converts.
那一窩侏儒
The runts of the litter.
丁梅斯黛爾是個小寶貝
Dimmesdale's little treasures!
我們有些人有不同看法
Some of us have other opinions.
白蘭因太太,
Mistress Prynne,
我希望你能跟我們住在這兒
I hope you'll stay with us
等你丈夫到了再說
until your husband's arrival.
你可真好，斯頓赫爾太太 不過我想
You're most kind, but I intend to find
自己找到房子，越快越好
a house of my own as soon as possible.
你自己住
On thine own?
是的
Why, yes.
在這兒一個年輕女人自己住可不好
It's not considered fitting for a young woman to live alone.
可是我丈夫吩咐我先找好住所等著他來
I've come first to prepare a place for his arrival,
所以我想先找房子
so that is what I intend to do.
白蘭因太太
Mistress Prynne.
我們的生活規定也許對新來者專橫了些
The rules we live by may seem arbitrary to a newcomer,
不過我們有慘痛的教訓
but we have learnt the hard way
如果在這兒沒有嚴格的規定
that without absolute order,
就無法生存
we cannot hope to survive here.
規定, 白蘭因太太
Rules, Mistress Prynne.
有序.
Order.
才能生存.
Survival.
你們是想要我違抗丈夫的意思
Would you have me disobey my husband?
- 我…… - 奇夫牧師, 你也許願意
- I... - Reverend, you might enjoy
讓我兒子陪你住，他叫布魯斯特
the company of my son, Brewster.
在大學學過神學
He studied Divinity.
哈佛不適合他
Harvard wasn't good enough for him,
所以他只好回家……
so he came home to make his fortune as a...
一般牧師的孩子睡覺的時候
Minister's sons all moaning the Lord's Prayer
嘴裏嘟噥著禱告詞
in their sleep.
每個人都得有自己的位置.
Everyone must find his place.
- 早上好, 白蘭因太太 - 早上好.
- Morning, Mistress Prynne. - Good morrow.
你到這兒來是不是想招他們的反感
So you intend on scandalising the town!
駕
Get up!
很好
Good!
我很煩
I confess,
我厭倦了唯唯諾諾的生活
I feel alone in a sea of conformists.
我們從哪兒開始找
Where should we begin our search?
海邊的懸崖上
On the cliffs by the sea.
不，那可不行
No, it's out of the question.
為什麼？
Why?
波靈被印第安人消滅掉以後
No one's lived by the sea
就沒有人住在海邊了
since the Indians wiped out Ballinger's Point.
我們就從那兒開始
I say we start there.
那就聽你的吧，白蘭因太太
Well, if you've decided.
布魯斯，那就是嗎?
Is that it, Brewster?
哦，太漂亮了
It's beautiful.
我無法想像
I tried to imagine what herlife was like
她來到這兒新世界之前的生活
before she came to the new world.
她丈夫為什麼要讓她一個人
Why did herhusband send heron ahead,
先來
alone?
是為了考驗她的忠誠
Was it a test ofherloyalty,
還是她的精神
orherspirit?
也許這是她丈夫本性的一面
Or was it in his nature to set traps
設置陷阱，希望人們能掉進來
forpeople in the hope they would fall into them?
好極了
It's perfect!
一輛車加一把好槍就能安家
With a cart and a musket, I could have a home here!
車，馬
A cart, a horse,
草叉子，犁
a pitchfork, a plow.
我能想出很多更好的事
I can think of better things
讓這雙漂亮的手去做 而不是讓它長繭
to do with these pretty hands than grow calluses on them.
我需要契約工，至少得兩個
I'll need indentured labor, at least two men.
- 這塊地需要排浪 - 你真頑固，白蘭因太太
- The land needs draining. - You are headstrong.
也許這是天生的
Perhaps it runs in the blood.
我聽說您父親就是這個脾氣
I'm told your father was too.
他是不是……
Is it true
真的欠你丈夫的債就拿你來頂債
he was in debt to your husband and you were the payment?
哦，這話讓你不高興了
I've said something to disturb you.
對不起
I'm sorry.
真對不起
I'm truly sorry.
哦，上帝，你真是太美了
God, thou art wondrous fair!
真疼
That hurt!
好，這會提醒你別再這麼做
Good. It'll remind you not to do it again.
菲絲？ 普魯頓斯？
Faith? Prudence?
你聽說了沒有？白蘭因太太有個浴盆
Did you hear Mistress Prynne has a bathing tub?
她是哪國人？法國人？
What is she, French?
兩先令？ 你願意出兩先令嗎？兩先令
2 Shillings. Will you bid 2 shillings?
兩個半先令，兩個半先令
2 and a half?
請注意先生們 願意出兩個半先令嗎？
Come on, gentlemen, do I have a bid for 3 shillings?
哦，到三先令了
3 shillings?
現在是三先令
有個多出嗎
Anyone else? Anyone else?
好，成交
Going for 3 shillings. Any other bids?
三先令賣給那位先生
Sold to the gentleman for 3 shillings.
- 下面我們要拍賣的這個是 - 那兩個
- Next we have this other one, - Those two.
他們的契約還有多久？
How much time left on their indenture?
大約三年
About 3 years, but,
不過應該是你丈夫或者你父親跟我談生意不是嗎
shouldn't your husband or father be doing business with me?
我的錢您看不上，先生？
Is my money no good to you, sir?
您的錢如同陽光下的美酒，太太
Your money's as fine as wine in the sunshine, Mistress.
如果您出的價錢公道 帶紅巾的女孩就送給你了
If you buy them at a just price, I'll throw in the girl in red.
她是奴隸
She's a slave!
她不會說話，這是個麻煩，天生就那樣
But she don't speak, if that be a problem. Born that way.
你就開個價吧
Name your just price.
您要是去林子，最好有我們陪著，太太
We'd best accompany you if your going to the forest.
不用擔心，鮑比先生 我走不遠
Don't worry Mr Bobbin. I shan't go far.
白蘭因太太? 白蘭因太太?
Mistress Prynne? Mistress Prynne?
白蘭因太太?
Mistress Prynne?
你在哪兒?
Where are you?
白蘭因太太, 你在哪兒?
Mistress Prynne, where are you?
是我找到她的
I found her.
- 不是你找到的 - 是我找到的
- You did not. - I did to.
- 你沒有 - 是我
白蘭因太太,
Mistress Prynne,
難道你忘了嗎？今天是安息日
Have you forgotten it is the Sabbath?
當然沒有，請原諒
Of course not. Forgive me.
我們特意來帶你去教堂
We've come by especially to bring you to church.
太感謝了
Thank you, so much.
不用管我
Please, go on without me.
我馬上跟著你們去
I will follow at once.
抓緊吧
Make haste.
好的，先生
Yes, sir.
好吧，姑娘
All right, girl,
來吧
Come on.
使勁
Oh goodnes!
後退，後退
Back up. Back up.
來吧，後退
Come on now, back up.
快點，退後，退後
Come on. Come on. Back up.
早上好
Good morrow.
要我幫你嗎？
May I be of assistance?
不下來怎麼幫
Not from up there.
來吧，後退
Come on.
後退呀
Come on. Steady. Steady.
好像我沒法讓它聽懂我的話
I can't make this horse understand me.
來，讓我試試
Let me try.
來吧，姑娘
Come on, girl.
用力，後退
Come on, back up!
使勁，使勁
Come on, girl.
姑娘，使勁
Come on. Come on.
恐怕陷得太深了
I'm afraid you're in too deep.
沒辦法上來 我抬一下試試
She'll not make it. Let me try this.
你能把它抬出來就好了
I do hope you can get it free.
禮拜儀式我趕不上了 大家肯定在說三道四
I'm already late for the service, and everyone's talking about me.
不如躲得遠遠的 不在乎他們的流言蜚語
I've been away and I'm quite behind on local gossip.
我在波靈買了套舊房子
I bought the old Newbury place out on Ballinger's Point.
嗯
Then,
我該向你道歉
I owe you an apology.
我一直在冒犯你
I've been trespassing.
那有個地方，我總在那兒洗澡
There's a place at the point where I like to bath.
真的？我不會收你太高的稅
Really? Well, I shan't charge too steep a tariff.
使勁姑娘，往後退
Come on, girl, back up!
- 使勁 - 一,
- Back up. - One,
二,
Two,
二， 三
Two. Three.
恐怕這車得陷到下個安息日了
I'm afraid this cart will be stuck here until Sabbath next
除非我找些人來幫忙
unless I gather hands to help.
介意跟我騎一匹馬嗎？
Would you care to ride with me?
跟你坐在一起？
On your horse, with you?
對，除非你會騎馬
Aye, unless you can ride.
我會騎
I can ride.
好，你騎我的馬，我騎你的
You take my horse and I'll take yours.
有一條近路，去匯合點
There's a shortcut to the meeting house,
不過不太好走
but it's a difficult road.
我能行，先生
I shall manage, sir.
- 你肯定嗎？ - 你帶路吧
- Are you certain? - Just you lead the way.
駕！駕！
Come on! Come on!
願上帝與你同在
May God be with you.
我相信已經同在了
I'm sure he already is.
可是你不去嗎
But aren't you coming to...
安息日平安
Good Sabbath to ye all.
朋友們
Friends,
滿懷偉大夢想的
and fellow voyagers,
同舟共濟的同事們
in the greatest of all dreams.
我們如同過去的 以色列人被挑選出來
We've been singled out, like Israel of old,
作為典範
to serve as a model.
所以如果能成功地
But if we are to succeed
建立我們新的耶路撒冷
in building our new Jerusalem,
我們的新的聖城
our "City on a Hill",
那愛的力量
then the power of love,
是的，上帝的愛
yea, His Divine Love,
我們必須萬眾一心
we must bind our hearts as one!
英國人和印第安人
English and Indian,
貴族和契約工 自由人和奴隸
gentry and indentured, free man and slaves,
將建立一個
and make of us
令全世界稱奇的榜樣
an example for all the world,
然後宣稱
to marvel at and proclaim:
這
"Here...
才是盡善盡美的標準
is the measure of perfection!
這
Here,
這是上帝的意旨
lives God's own!"
可我們沒有通過這一檢驗
But we are not succeeding in that test.
我們失敗了 為什麼？
We are failing! And why?
因為我們貪婪無度
Because we covet, nay,
我們奢求我屬於我們的東西
we lust after what is not ours.
我們奢求印第安人富饒的土地
Be it for the rich land of our Indian brothers,
奢求榮譽
be it for glory,
奢求利益，奢求報復
for profits or for revenge.
需要我說出每個人的
Need I read the secret
心聲嗎
of every heart?
好，你們需要我就說
I will if you want.
你們需要我就說
Yea, I will if you want.
我把你們心中的秘密
I will lay open the secrets
敞開於上帝的面前
before the eyes of God!
任何貪婪者都是我們敵人 上帝這樣說
What thou lusteth after is my enemy, sayeth the Lord God.
只有我能夠滿足你們
For only I shall consume thee,
也能毀滅你們
only I shall fill thee up.
如果你們違背我的意旨
If thou failest to heed my commandments,
那我的拳頭
then my fist
將如石頭一樣落在你們的身上
shall descend on thee like a stone!
而且我的劍會把你們切成肉泥
And thy sword shall cut thee into bloody parts,
甚至你們的記憶也將
and even thy memories shall be sacrificed
永遠隨風而去
to the winds for all time!
上帝保佑你們
May God bless you,
保佑每一個人
each and every one of you.
阿門
Am幯.
阿瑟，請你允許我介紹一位新加入聖會的女士
Allow me to present a newcomer to our congregation,
羅傑·白蘭因太太
Mistress Roger Prynne.
羅傑太太？
Mistress Roger?
她的丈夫，一位大名鼎鼎的醫生就要來和她團聚了
Aye, her husband, a renowned physician will join her before...
丁梅斯黛爾牧師和我已經……
Reverednd Dimmesdale and I have already...
我幫過白蘭因太太 她的馬車在森林裏陷住了
I helped when her cart got stuck in the woods.
我非常喜歡你的布道
I greatly enjoyed your sermon.
如此年輕面演講時又如此激情四射，真是難得
It's rare for a man so young to speak with such passion.
是的，不知道為什麼
For some reason,
我今天非常有激情
I felt most inspired today.
歡迎您和您的丈夫加入我們聖會
We welcome you and your husband to our congregation.
媽媽！媽媽！
Mother! Mother!
哦，你在這兒, 海絲特.
There you are, Hester.
見見我的朋友萊尼·莫斯，小學校長
Meet my friend, Running Moose. He's our schoolmaster.
想來點點心嗎，
And I'm sure you'd like some refreshment.
哦，是的 你也教英國孩子嗎，萊尼·莫斯先生
Do you teach the English children as well Mr Running Moose?
在這兒他們都叫我約翰或約翰尼
They call me John or Johnny here.
我們盡力教，不過英國人轉的有點慢
We try our best, but the English are a bit slow-witted.
轉得慢？
Slow-witted?
約翰尼愛開玩笑 他是我們的第一個印第安信徒
Johnny's a bit of a jester, but he was our first praying Indian.
這位是我最好的朋友
My best friend in the colony.
阿瑟
Arthur,
- 這位是…… - 我們見過面了
- this is Mistress... - We've already met.
對不起
Excuse me.
這兒太像家了
So like home.
不過那些樹的後面 想必是一片野蠻之地
Yet beyond those trees I suspect a savagery,
充滿野性
of savage passions,
黑暗和未馴服
dark and untamed.
哦，丁梅斯黛爾牧師 見過我們年輕的朋友了嗎？
Reverend Dimmesdale, have you met our young friend?
是的，我們見過了
Yes, we've met.
白蘭因太太和我是坐同一條船來的
Mistress Prynne and I traveled out on the same ship.
將來我要嫁給他
I'm going to marry him one day.
你閉上嘴，我才要嫁給他 對嗎？白蘭因太太？
No you're not, I'm going to aren't I Mistress Prynne?
- 嫁給誰 -當然是丁梅斯黛爾牧師了
- Marry whom? - Reverend Dimmesdale, of course!
"偉大的最終審判日簡述".
"A Short Description of the Great and Last Judgement".
哦, "教堂戒律論壇".
Well, "Platform for Church Discipline".
都是些小冊子
They're all tracts!
"主婦…… "
"The Goodwife's Manual... "
"主婦用動物飼養手冊"
for Animal Husbandry"
我相信我們見過了
I believe we've already met.
哦，是的，對，對，對不起 我……
Oh, yes, I... I'm sorry, I didn't realize.
不，不，不，我應該先打個招呼
I should have announced my presence.
你在看什麼
What are you reading?
- "慶祝神", 作者是…… - 約翰·密爾頓
- "Comus", it's by John - John Milton.
知道，我讀過
I know it. I've read it.
你讀過？
Have you?
是的，我在家不只洗洗涮涮
I'm not all counterpanes and coverlets.
只要有空我就會讀點什麼的
Every spare moment, I read.
我也一樣
I'm the same.
這房子裏的書我都看過 有些讀過幾遍了
I've read every book in this room. Some of them several times.
"主婦動物飼養手冊"你也讀過嗎？
Even "Manual for Animal Husbandry?"
讀得最高興的一本
A most exhiliarating read.
你真的喜歡我的布道嗎？
So, did you truly enjoy my sermon?
是的，很喜歡，非常有技巧
Yes, it was most skilful.
顯然社會對你非常器重
Clearly your congregation reverences you.
你不會喜歡,我們這是世界的邊緣 顯然達不到你們倫敦的水準
You liked it not. We don't come up to London standards.
正好相反，我被你的激情感動，我說過
To the contrary. I was moved by your passion.
而且
And?
什麼？
Well,
你的手第一次揮動的時候
when your fist struck your hand,
像把劍一樣劃過空氣
and sliced through the air like a sword,
我當時就在想
I found myself wondering
你如此激情的演講後面會藏著多大的痛苦啊
what manner of pain lay beneath such forceful oratory.
你真是口無遮攔，白蘭因太太
Your tongue knows no rules, Mistress Prynne.
如果真有痛苦，牧師
And if it did, Reverend,
那布道又有什麼用
what purpose would it serve?
我認為全知的上帝
And here I thought comprehending God
會成為我最大的挑戰
was to be my greatest challenge.
怎麼了，牧師？
Yes, Reverend?
今天早上在森林裏
This morning in the forest,
為什麼不說你已經結婚了？
why did you not say you were married?
為什麼不說你是個牧師？
Why did you not say you were a minister?
再見, 白蘭因太太
Good day, Mistress Prynne.
您好, 白蘭因太太
Good morrow, Mistress Prynne.
您好
Good morrow.
想來杯蘋果酒嗎？
You care for a cup of cider?
我們好像是鄰居
We are your neighbours, it seems.
喜歡今天上午的布道嗎？
Did you like the sermon this morning?
我坐在那兒看到你聽得挺高興的
From where I sat it seemed it did please thee.
我非常喜歡聽
I liked it very much.
我想那位年輕的牧師很……
I thought the young minister very...
英俊？
Handsome?
哈里森·希本斯
Harriet Hibbons.
來吧
Ruth?
你好
How do you do?
來見見幾個沒被邀請去參加
Come and meet some of the others who were not invited
總督家小舞會的人
to the Governer's shindig.
莎琳·肖特, 白蘭因太太
Sally Short, Mistress Prynne.
您好
How do you do?
您到的時候我在碼頭上
I was on the dock when you arrived.
瑪麗·盧林斯
Mary Rollins.
哦，瑪麗不大喜歡說話
Mary don't like to speak much.
擺脫了那些野蠻人的糾纏還不到半年多
She's only been free from the savages this half year.
還有莫特娜，她不信任英國人，
And Matona don't trust the English, do you dear?
對嗎？親愛的
Mistress Prynne?
謝謝您 不，我不喝酒
Thank you, no. I never imbibe.
看起來，您收集了一些上好的草藥
You've gathered some fine Balm of Gilead,
牧羊人錢包，蓍草
Shepherd's Purse, yarrow.
您認識這些草藥
You know your plants?
是的，我可以背誦藥典
I do. I recite "Culpepper" by heart.
真的？
Really?
要是嚴重的燒傷應該用什麼藥醫治
Then what would you use to heal a bad burn?
我見過甜洋草的奇效
I've seen sweet fern work miracles,
不過藥典建議用黑莓和紅血松
but Culpepper suggests blackberry and red cedar.
哦，你們聽見了嗎
Well, you hear that.
我覺得非常幸運，我丈夫有一個大書房
My husband has a very large library
我可以自己找書去看
and I was able to school myself.
喜歡我們的新聖地嗎？
How do you like our new Jerusalem?
你覺得太肅穆了？
Sober enough for you?
對
Aye,
太肅穆了
sober enough.
我還是想念舞會啊
What I miss is the dancing.
舞會？
Dancing?
我剛來的時候
When first we came,
他們都圍著五朔柱跳舞
they'd be dancing round the maypole.
過節的時候都唱亂七八糟的歌
Feast days we'd sing bawdy songs.
人們那時候不怕出醜
People weren't afraid to play the fool.
我們能教會熊跳舞
We'd teach the bears to dance.
現在，人們的臉色越來越沉越來越木
Now days, everybody getting more and more sourfaced and ponderous.
原來的五朔柱變成了鞭打柱
And a whipping post stands where the mayppole used to be.
只有我們幾個沒有忘記怎麼笑， 對嗎？姑娘們
But there's a few of us who haven't forgotten to laugh.
能見到你們我非常高興
It's been a pleasure meeting you all.
我很不情願告辭
I'm sorry I must take my leave,
可我必須走了，我可不想在夜裏陷在這個森林裏
but I don't want to be stuck in the wilds at night.
這話我聽起來很奇怪
There are things that sound to me,
夜間的荒野是我的領地
the wilds at night are my natural territory.
尤其在月圓之夜
Particulary when there's a full moon.
您想用咒語來嚇唬我嗎
Do you try to frighten me with this witch talk?
不, 白蘭因太太
Not so, Mistress Prynne.
可我能看到別人看不到的東西
But I can see what others cannot.
這當然是個咒語
Be a curse, to be sure,
我能讀懂人的心
but I know the hearts of men.
我的心告訴你什麼？
And what does my heart tell you?
你是個漂亮女人，白蘭因太太
You're a most comely woman.
男人擔心雖然能握到少女的手
Let a man tremble who wins the hand of a maid,
可得不到它心中的全部激情
but possesses not the full passion of her heart.
我丈夫沒有什麼可怕的
My husband has nothing to fear.
再見，希本斯太太
Good day Mistress Hibbons.
再見, 白蘭因太太
Good day, Mistress Prynne.
你好, 古蒂·高德威克.
Good day, Goody Gotwick.
我帶了這些給丁梅斯黛爾牧師
I brought these for Reverend Dimmesdale.
牧師可能正在工作，太太
The Reverend be occupied with his work, Missus.
把書放桌上，我保證他能拿到
Leave them books on the table and I'll be sure he gets them.
您好，牧師
Good morrow, Reverend.
您好，白蘭因太太
Good morrow, Mistress Prynne.
知道您很想讀一些新書
Knowing you hunger for new reading,
我從我丈夫書房裏拿了一些給你
I brought you some books.
您太客氣了
How courteous of you.
請吧
Please.
我很抱歉安息日那天我說了很冒昧的話
I must apologize for my forthrightness on Sabbath last.
我從小到大為自己的心直口快挨了不少的責罵
I've earned a few reprimands for speaking too bluntly.
我，我也應該道歉
I owe an apology, too.
我不明白我為什麼會如此反感那種
I can't understand why I took such offence
率真的評論
to such a simple comment.
我想知道
But I have wondered
您怎麼能夠
how you were able
對我的本性
to see so deeply
看得如此深刻
into my nature.
也許我是個女巫
Perhaps I'm a witch.
我不能再讓您費心了
I must be keeping you from your chores.
謝謝您的書，白蘭因太太
Thank you for the books.
再見
Good day.
我很抱歉，我手上全是墨水
I'm sorry. My hands are covered in ink.
我一直
I've been
整天都在忙活著翻譯的事
hovered over my translations all day.
翻譯？
Translations?
是的，我一直打算
Aye. I'm attempting to
把聖經翻譯成本地的印第安語言
translate the Bible into the local Indian language,
阿耳岡昆語
Algonquin.
雄心勃勃的計劃
What an ambitious undertaking.
可是我聽說印第安人不聽聖經的指引
But I'm told the Indians don't want to be guided by our Bible.
所以跟他們的戰爭不可避免
That war with them is inevitable.
有人是這樣想，但是他們錯了
Some think that way, but they're wrong.
因為印第安人不太容易被征服，
The Indians, born from a certain liberty,
他們天生地桀驁不馴
take not easily to bridle and bit.
男人本色
No man should.
嗯……
Well...
怎麼？
What?
怎麼了？
你往臉上塗了墨水
You keep putting ink on your face.
哦
Oh, I do.
知道了
There you are.
希望你能喜歡那些書
I do hope you enjoy the books.
謝謝
Thank you.
再見
Good day.
米杜芭？
Mituba?
那只是個浴盆 不是撒旦的玩偶
'Tis only a bathing tub, not a toy of Satan.
白蘭因太太?
Mistress Prynne?
丁梅斯黛爾牧師
Reverend Dimmesdale!
- 你嚇了我一跳 - 對不起，我不是故意的
- You frightened me. - I'm sorry. I didn't mean to.
不，是個很大的驚喜
It's a wonderful surprise.
- 這兒真漂亮 - 是的，也很嚇人
- It's beautiful. - Yes, and frightening.
伊甸園不過如此
Just as Eden must have been.
美妙無比
So untouched.
是不是可以大聲地發誓說
Does it not cry out with it's promise,
這裏的一切可以重新開始
that everything can begin anew?
我把您的書帶來了
I brought back your books.
你不可能在四天的時間全看完了
You couldn't have read them all in four days.
哦不，看完了，大多都看了兩遍
Oh no, I did. I read most of them twice.
謝謝你
Thank you.
不客氣
You're welcome.
再見
Farewell.
海絲特...
Hester...
我不是你看到的那樣
I'm not the man I seem.
我一直都住在這裏，我的目標明確
I've lived here all my life, my purpose clear.
可現在我願意拿我的生命，我的職位，我的靈魂冒險
But now I'd risk everything, my life, my ministry, my soul
只為與您獨處幾分鐘
just to spend a few moments alone with you.
上帝幫助我，海絲特.
God help me, Hester.
我愛你
I love thee.
上帝幫助我，我也愛你
God help me. I love thee too.
哦，我們迷失方向了嗎？
Oh God. Have we lost our way?
不
No!
我夢見你向我傾吐心聲
I dreamed of thee speaking thy heart.
我一直在祈求一直在渴望
I have prayed for it even as I have dreaded it.
見到你之前我究竟是生還是死
Was I alive before I laid eyes on thee?
我們該怎麼辦
What shall we do?
我不知道
I know not.
說點什麼讓我停止
Say something to end it,
我無能為力
for I have not the power.
我也是
Nor I.
不，
Nay!
我們會因此被絞死
We could be hanged for this.
我置你於危險之中
I've put you in too much danger,
我一定要停止們並且走開，再也不能跟你說話了
and I must end it by walking away and never speaking with you again.
走吧
Go then.
信守你的諾言
Do as you promised.
整個漫長的夏天，白蘭因太太和丁梅斯黛爾牧師
Throughout the long summer, Mistress Prynne and the Reverend
想方設法避免見面
avoided each other at all costs.
白蘭因太太幾乎不鎮子上來，丁梅斯黛爾牧師躲進了荒野
Mistress Prynne rarely went to town and the Reverend escaped to the wilds
只有印第安人
with the Indians
和忠實的約翰尼與之為伴
and faithful Johnny Sassamon for company.
殖民地照常舉辦
And the colony organized
選舉日週年慶祝
it's annual election day as usual.
沒人知道他們之中
No one the wiser that there existed among them
有兩顆心正在與愛抗爭
two hearts struggling against a love
而這種愛，卻與日俱增
that grew stronger with each passing day.
他在說什麼
Johnny Sassamon says they've attacked the "Intrepid".
阿瑟?
What's he saying,
他說塔蘭泰人
Arthur?
攻擊了一艘英國船，無畏號
The Tarrantines
船上的人都被殺了
attacked an English ship, the Intrepid.
"白蘭因".
All were massacred.
"羅傑·白蘭因醫生".
"Prynne".
白蘭因太太.
"Doctor Roger Prynne".
我是作為你的牧師來這兒的
Mistress Prynne.
請進
I'm here as your minister.
有一支印第安人
Come in.
他們攻擊了我們的船
There was an attack,
他們說
an Indian attack on one of our ships.
船上的人都被殺了
They say that,
我非常遺憾
all aboard were massacred.
給您帶來這個噩耗
I regret to be...
我該走了，請您節哀吧
the one to bring you this sad news.
你肯定沒有一個倖存者嗎？
I'll leave you to your mourning.
他們說海浪把屍體都沖走了
Are you certain none survived?
上帝寬恕我
They say that the tide washed away the bodies.
為獲得自由我祈求了很久
God forgive me!
他的死不是你造成的，海絲特
I've prayed so long to be set free.
上帝……
You did not cause his death, Hester.
帶走了你丈夫
God...
是的，這是上帝對我的回復嗎？
took your husband.
上帝是這樣做的嗎？
But was it an answer to my prayers?
也許吧
Does He work like that?
如果在它看來沒有其它辦法
Perhaps.
讓我們在一起
If in His eyes there was no other way
我得看看法律怎麼說
we could be together.
服喪期多久，要等多長時間
I must know what the law is.
一個月？六個月？怎麼？
The mourning, how long must one wait?
但是這樣無法證明他已經絕對死亡
1 month? Six months? What?
我們就必須要等七年之後才能公諸於世
Where there is no absolute proof of death,
七年?
7 years must pass before we're free to be seen in public.
是的
7 years?
祝賀你，麥特坎姆
Yes...
我們一直是敵人
Greetings, Metacomet.
但是現在我們必須團結起來
We have been
打擊貪婪的英國人
enemies.
不然他們會把我們趕下海
But now Tarrantine
所以我們給你帶來了這個禮物
and Wampanoag must unite
一個英國醫生
to fight
我們團結起來
the greedy English.
你說怎麼樣
before theypush us into
印第安人對你殘忍嗎，瑪麗？
the sea.
我兒子死後
Were the Indians cruel to you, Mary?
他們對我真的挺好的
After my little one died,
說句心裏話
they treated me fair and square.
謝謝
If truth be told,
我回來後你們對我的態度才算是殘忍
cruel is how you folks have treated me since I come home.
沒有哪件事不是逼著我幹的
Thank you.
只要一想想被野人佔有
I didn't do nothing that wasn't forced on me!
我就覺得噁心
The thought of being taken by a savage
野人是在馬背上做那件事的
makes me sick to my stomach.
一邊跑一邊做
Well, they do it on the backs of their horses,
海絲特，你沒事吧
ridin' across the land.
對，我沒事，我只是累了
Hester, you all right?
瑪麗說得對
Yes, I'm just tired.
你管他們叫野人
Mary's right.
我可以說說你亡夫做過的好事
You call them savages.
不過那是你們結婚前的事了
I could tell you a thing or two
你這個蕩婦
about your husband before he tied the knot with you.
哈洛德絕不會跟妓女有什麼瓜葛
Stupid slut!
你以為沒有？
Harold would never had nothing to do with no whore!
我甚至看見過一個滿嘴牧師聖經的牧師
You think not?
跟印第安女人鬼混
I've even seen one of your windy ministers
為了更加快活他腳下還墊著聖經
pokin' an Injun girl,
怪不得他們都說聖經能讓人昇華
standin' on a bible so he could roger her better.
我拒絕與嘲笑聖經的人呆在同一個房間裏
They always said the Scriptures should uplift you!
好的
I refuse to be with those who would mock the Holy Book!
短時間內她不會回來了
Well,
對她來說是個解脫
she'll not be coming back soon.
可是我們教友派認為聖經本身並不是宗教
Good riddance to her!
只不過是儀式和歷史而已
We Quakers believe that the Scriptures be not religion,
我同意
but only the ceremony and history of it.
那些戒律不過是凡夫俗子的憑空想像
I agree.
我的的精神才是真正來自天堂的聲音
For are not the laws of men but the imagination of mortals,
海絲特
and the inner spirit the true voice of Heaven?
但願你不是在暗示
Hester,
你可以直接通神吧
I pray you're not sayin' you talk directly
你不知道
to the Deity?
只有那些拿高俸祿的聖經巨人才能通神
Don't you know that
小心點，孩子
only paid Bible-thumpers can do that?
不然他們會像談論我那樣談論你
Have a care, child,
我知道有些人認為
or they'll talking of you the way they talk of me!
這樣說是大不敬
I know some consider it blasphemous to say this,
可從小時候起
but I do talk to God.
我就和上帝對話，上帝也回應我
I have since I was a small child.
羅傑·白蘭因太太
And He answers me.
受馬塞諸塞海灣殖民地總督之命
Mistress Roger Prynne...
明天上午八點
by order of the Governor of Masachusetts Bay Colony,
你要接受眾長者和執法官的審判
you are ordered to appear before the magistrates
不得有誤
at eight tomorrow morn!
白蘭因太太,
Don't be tardy!
這些先生指控你離經叛道
Mistress Prynne,
你是否跟其他人說過 戒律只是凡人的想像
these gentlemen have laid a charge ofheresy againstyou.
他們稱之為異端者的聚會
Tell me how it is the laws ofmen are the imagination ofmortals?
不止是談論與野人的通姦
It is the meetings thatyou call heresy.
墮落的女人對好人大肆辱罵
Lascivious talk offornication with savages.
沒有一個有資格的男人加以指導
Fallen women who tell lies about good citizens.
這些女人就會信口胡言，說出大不敬的話來
This is what comes when there is no qualified man present
先生，如果女人的談話是信口胡言
to guide these women in their untutored chatterings.
那為什麼聖經會告誡我們，讓女人做女人的教師呢
If the discourse of women is untutored chattering,
海絲特，請您停止這種聚會
why does the Bible teach that women shall be the teachers of women?
不，先生 我不會停止聚會
Hester, we ask that you cease these meetings.
阿瑟，請加入我們
No, sirs. I'll not stop the meetings.
我剛剛釣魚回來先生
Arthur. Please join us.
我站在原地你會感謝我的
I've been fishing, sir..
- 好吧，請坐下 - 我想傳喚一位證人
You may thank me to remain where I am.
很重要嗎？
- Please be seated. - Call our first witness.
是的，這非常重要
Is it truly of import?
好吧，傳你的證人
Yes, it is of great consequence.
古蒂·高德威克？
Very well, call your witness.
請你站起來，古蒂
Goody Gotwick?
你跟我妻子透露我了最讓人擔心的一件事情
Stand up, Goody.
告訴我，一個女人在早晨嘔吐
You revealed to my wife something very disturbing.
意味著什麼
Tell me, what does it mean when a woman
在早晨，而且不只是在一個地方嘔吐
vomits in the morning hours?
我只見她吐過一次
And vomits more than once in the morning hours?
是嗎，還有
I only saw her the one time.
古蒂·姆提爾看見她在市場吐過
Yes. And?
你是否懷孕了，太太
Goody Mortimer saw her get sick in the market.
回答問題，女人
Are you with child?
你肚子裏是不是懷著野種
Answer your betters, woman!
是的
Do you carry a bastard child in yur womb?
孩子的父親是誰？
Yes.
如果說出躲在你裙子後面的男人你就無罪
Who is the father?
我們要絞死那個私通者
You are innocent next to the one who would hide behind your skirts.
我不會說出他的名字，先生
We would hang that fornicator!
我告訴你他的名字
I'll not reveal the name, sir.
他叫撒旦
I will tell you his name!
他叫貪慾
His name is Lucifer!
他叫十惡不赦
His name is Legion!
先生們
His name is lust!
你們想怎麼了斷
Gentlemen,
你很清楚沒有法律禁止懷孕
What do you hope to accomplish?
可有法律禁止通姦
You know there is no law against pregnancy.
只有她丈夫活著那才能叫通姦
But there is against adultery.
你是不是懷了野種
It would only adultery if her husband were found to be alive.
我們要絞死那通姦犯
以通姦罪把她關起來那聚會也就能阻止
總督大人
The meetings will stop!
如果你知道那個男人，你還會把海絲特·白蘭因關起來嗎
Governor,
她跟你坦白過嗎
if you knew the name of this man, would you punish Hester Prynne?
我跟他什麼都沒說過
Has she confessed the name to you?
- 真相是什麼， 阿瑟. - 他對我的私事根本不瞭解
I've confessed nothing!
- 說出真相，阿瑟 - 作為我的牧師，他將救我於你們的魔掌
- Tell us the truth, Arthur. - He knows nothing of my affairs.
可我不怕你們的懲罰
He speaks as my pastor to spare me your harsh hand.
我敬重也很愛這個孩子的父親
But I fear not your punishments!
隨你們怎麼說 他將是我今生真正的丈夫
I love and honor the man who has fathered this child!
而我根本不可能 說出任何給他帶來傷害的話
And say what you will, he is my true husband for life,
那好吧，太太，你讓我別無選擇
and I shall furnish no information which might cause him harm.
你被捕了
Very well, you leave me no choice.
你為什麼要抓她
You're under arrest.
讓我跟這女人單獨呆一會兒
Is this your new Jerusalem?
- 我肯定能讓她說出他的名字 - 很好，阿瑟，你會有這個機會，我保證
Let me have a moment alone with the woman.
先生們
- I can draw the name from her. - You shall have your chance.
我考慮過所有意見之後
Gentlemen.
我決定必須允許阿瑟 單獨跟白蘭因太太談談
I've considered all the arguments
海絲特·白蘭因
and decided Arthur is allowed to speak to Mistress Prynne alone.
把你的手放在聖經上
Hester Prynne,
我們禱告
place your hand on the Good Book.
Let us pray.
你為什麼不告訴我
我害怕
Why did you not tell me?
我以為拚命幹活就能流產
I was afraid.
我必須說出真相
I thought if I worked hard, I would miscarry.
不，不能說
I must go to Bellingham with the truth.
對他們來說你是聖徒 他們會因為背叛而絞死你
No, you must not!
那就絞死我吧 也比讓你代我受過要好
You are a saint to these people! They'll hang you for betraying them!
可他們沒有關我的理由
I prefer to hang, than allow you to suffer for me.
- 等他們吵累了就會把我放出去的 - 我瞭解斯頓赫爾
They've no case against me!
你在挑戰他
- When they tire, they'll release me. - I know Stonehall.
他不會放過你
You've challenged him,
除非你變得恭順並承認自己有罪
and he'll not release you
你認為我們有罪嗎？
until you are humbled and have recanted your sins.
我知道沒有
Do you believe we've sinned?
我們相愛本身就是一種昇華 我們感覺如此美妙難道你忘了嗎
I know not.
我沒有忘
What happen between us had a consecration. Have you forgotten?
阿瑟，我知道你想說出來
I've not forgotten!
你人本性決定你想說出真相
Arthur, I know you want to speak out.
可你那樣會毀掉自己
Your nature cries out for it.
也會剝奪我反抗這種偽善的權利
But you risk your own ruin and deny me
士兵
my right to stand up to this hypocrisy.
如果我想跟你說話
Soldier!
我會把手絹繫在這個窗戶上
If I need you to speak,
我愛你，海絲特
I'll tie this handkerchief from the window.
可你的勇氣讓我害怕
I love thee woman,
我會照你說的做
but your strength frightens me.
阿門
I'll do what you ask.
願上帝與你同在
Amen.
我相信他已經同在了
God be with you.
先生們
I'm sure he already is.
白蘭因太太在這裏關了五個月
Gentlemen,
而沒有受到任何合法的審判，為什麼？
Mistress Prynne has been there more than 5 months
甚至連落後的普利毛斯人都指責 這樣對待她是野蠻行為
without any legal justification.
我也很想把她釋放，阿瑟 這件事讓我在家裏不得安生
Even in Plymouth they regard this as barbaric!
現在是人們看著我們 一個星期接一個星期找她談
I'd like to free her. At home, I have no peace on this.
卻只能無功而返
But the people see us go to her week after week, caps in hand,
這個女人不認罪，不懺悔
only to be turned away.
沒有當眾鞭打她已經算是她幸運了
The woman is unrepentant!
我很奇怪，奇夫牧師. 你剛來時是很理智的
She's fortunate we haven't beaten her publicly!
我來這兒，先生 是要找到一種有效的秩序
I'm surprised at you Reverend. You came here a man of reason.
可我找到的卻是虛偽的巢穴
I came here expecting some semblance of order.
先生，如果你不阻止這種異端
Instead I find a den of fractiousness!
我和我妻子決定返回英國
Sir, if you do not stem this dissent,
而且帶走所有的教區居民
my wife and I will return to England.
她只要表示
And take our parishioners!
一點點悔悟就可以了
If only she would give us
如果我父親能做決定
a small sign of contrition.
他會把把我的身世透露出來 並瞭解這件事
Ifit had been up to him, my father,
- 讓開 - 可是為了我母親的意願，他不能這樣做
he would have ended it and revealed the truth ofmy origins.
- 不許探視 - 簡直可惡之極
But bound by my mother's wish, he could not.
他每天都去看媽媽，每天都被拒絕
每當他在窗戶上看到那標記時
He went every day to see her and was refused.
他都覺得他應該站出來，說出真相
His eye everon that window forhersign that it was time
白蘭因反覆無常的本性
to come forward with the truth.
在英國可曾出現過
Had there been flashes ofPrynne's unstable nature before
沒有人知道
in England?
現在他雖然離開了清教徒社會
No one knows.
可他還是受困於日漸增多的清規戒律中
But now, free from Puritan society,
這些戒律強大得連印第安人都覺得可怕
he was increasingly seized by spirits so powerful
他的身體裏一定有幽靈
they were terrifying even to the Indians.
他會給我們帶來厄運
He has a ghost in him.
送他回家吧
He'll bring us bad luck.
寬恕我，上帝
Send him home.
我已經背離了你，我的聖父
Forgive me, Lord,
請寬恕我
forI have turned from my Heavenly Father.
帶我重回你的懷抱
Forgive me.
可憐的孩子，他們怎麼能不管你
Lord, bring me back to thy bosom.
我很高興你在這兒
God's teeth, child! How could they leave you thus?
六個月都沒有人來看我
I'm so glad you're here!
我們想來，親愛的 可他們不讓進來
6 months and not one visitor.
你的奴隸每天都來 現在，疼得厲害嗎？
Some of us came, my dear, but we were turned away.
- 從沒停過 - 來吧
Your slave came every day. How quick are the pains?
喝一口這個
- They're not stopping. - Here.
我告訴你，這次別拒絕我的蘋果酒
Take a sip of this.
丁梅斯黛爾牧師想盡了方法想把你弄出去
I wager you won't refuse my cider this time.
- 還要嗎？ - 是的
Rvd. Dimmesdale tried always to get you freed.
哦，親愛的，來吧，深呼吸 深呼吸
- Another? - Yes.
我在這兒，抓緊我，很好，姑娘
All right, breathe deep. Breathe deep.
放鬆，放鬆
Hold on to me! Good girl!
讓我看看，讓我看看
Easy, easy.
好的好的，一切都好
Let me see.
快了，我親愛的，是時候了
All's well. All's well. It's close.
你坐起來
It's very close. Come, my dear. It's time.
對，好姑娘
Up you sit.
下來一點
Good girl. There.
這個孩子生得真是時候
Move down a little. Good.
我們可有事做了
This child is ready to be born.
好的
We've work to do!
我沒想到他們關我這麼久
There.
讓我說
How could they keep me here so long?
Well, I'll say this,
你一定有鋼鐵般的意志
要是換了男人 他們早就死了
you must have a will of iron.
好的，親愛的，現在
When you take on the men, it leads to death.
深呼吸，深呼吸
All right, my dear. Chin down and bear down hard!
再使勁，再來
More and harder!
好，好，對
Harder! Good!
放鬆
Good girl. That's it.
Easy.
好，好，放鬆
上帝是在懲罰我
Good. Easy.
說真的，懲罰你
Are you sure God's not punishing me?
是要給你個孩子
To be sure he's punishing you.
用勁，再來
He be giving you a child!.
哦，頭出來了
Now. Gently.
看見了，看見了
Now the head is coming.
慢點，肩膀出來了
The head is through.
放鬆，放鬆
Just a little more. Easy.
是個丫頭
Easy. Easy.
上帝，謝謝你
She'd here!
是的
Oh, thank you, God!
小寶貝，是的
Yes!
是的
Little Pearl. Yes!
我的，她在這兒
Yes!
她在這兒
Harriet, she's here!
坐下吧，太太
She's here.
開始吧，牧師.
Sit there, Mistress.
我讓他們去給你和孩子拿乾淨的衣服
Proceed, Reverend.
我帶來了好消息
I'll have them fetch fresh clothes for you and the babe.
我已經說服了總督
I bring good news.
將你釋放
I've prevailed upon the Governor.
不過根據法律
You are to be freed.
你將會被送到絞刑架
But by law...
接受審訊
you'll be brought to the scaffold
海絲特
for reprimand.
不管他們說什麼
Hester.
求你
Whatever is said,
假裝誠心悔恨
please,
就算不為我，也要為了孩子
be as contrite as your conscience permits.
求你不要再激怒他們 有時
If not for my sake, for the babe's.
我來給這個孩子做洗禮
I beg you, don't anger them further!
我快著急死了
I've come to baptize the babe.
我每天都來
I've died not seeing you.
我給這個孩子做洗禮
I came every day.
珠兒
I baptize this child,
珠兒？
Pearl.
以聖父
聖子
In the name of the Father,
聖靈的名義
and the son,
願上帝祝福你
and the Holy Ghost.
關愛你
May the Lord bless thee,
保佑你
and care for thee,
阿門
and watch over thee.
釋放這個女人
Amen.
就等於慫恿每一個妻子
Freeing this woman
背叛她的丈夫
is an invitation to every wife
每一個孩子背叛他的父母
to defy her husband.
不，應該把她釋放
Every child it's parent!
什麼？
No, she should be released.
不要把她關進監獄
What?
而要把監獄建在她的心裏
You don't put her in prison,
這樣每次大家看她的時候
you put the prison in her.
她的靈魂將重新打上罪惡的烙印
So each time someone sees her,
真是個好主意，親愛的
her sin will be marked into her soul afresh.
以國王的名義讓步
Cunningly contrived, my dear.
我們祝福馬塞諸塞海岸殖民地裏
Make way in the King's name.
不公正的行為被暴露在陽光下
A blessing on the righteous Colony of Massachusetts,
今天在場的人都知道
where iniquity is dragged into the sunlight!
羅傑·白蘭因太太
Know ye
一直因為其背叛和通姦行為
that Mistress Roger Prynne
而受懲罰
has been ordered
如果以後能確定
to bear punishment for fornication and adultery.
她的丈夫還活著
If it be determined later
那她還將受到更加嚴厲的懲罰
that her husband be still alive,
也就是接受絞刑至死
she may face a most severe penalty,
上帝保佑
which is to be hanged by the neck until dead.
尊敬的總督閣下簽署
Pray, silence, for his Excellency,
海絲特·白蘭因,
the Governor.
雖然你沒有表現出真誠
Hester Prynne,
不過你仍然有機會悔過
though you show no modesty in you apparel,
悔過吧，海絲特
yet you have a chance, still, to repent your sins.
孩子，你是否相信你犯了罪
Yes, Hester, repent!
我相信你們認為我有罪
Child, don't you believe you have sinned?
可誰知道上帝是不是認同你們
I believe I have sinned in your eyes,
婦人
but who is to know if God shares your views?
你不要超越上天仁慈的界限
Woman,
丁梅斯黛爾牧師 你是她的牧師
transgress not the limits of Heaven's mercy!
跟她談談
Reverend Dimmesdale, you are her pastor.
為了我們大家，開導她 別讓她冥頑不化
Speak to her for all our sakes!
跟她談談，牧師
Soften her, her hardness her obstinacy!
跟她談談吧，我的兄弟
Listen to the Reverend!
勸她說出真相
Speak to the woman, my brother.
海絲特·白蘭因,
Exalt her to confess the truth!
聽見這些好人的話了嗎
Hester Prynne,
你可以看出我承擔了多大的責任
you hear what these good men say,
為了你靈魂的安寧
and see the accountablity under which I labor.
我責令你
For your soul's peace,
說出另一個
I charge thee
有罪者的名字
speak out the name
你不要因為
of your fellow sinner.
錯誤的同情和關愛而保持沉默了
Be not silent
相信我，如果那個人站出來
for some mistaken pity or tenderness for him.
與你並肩站在這裏受辱
For believe me, if he could
要好過讓他
step down and stand beside you on your pedestal of shame,
帶著一顆愧疚之心悔恨終生
it would be better than to
你的沉默能夠為他做什麼
carry a guilty heart through life.
你是想誘惑他
What can your silence do for him,
還是想強迫他
except to tempt him?
背負另一個罪名
And compel him
說吧
to add hypocrisy to sin?
她不肯說
Speak.
以上帝的名義，絞死他
She will not speak.
絞死他
In the name of the Lord, name him!
- 快說吧 - 他是誰
Name him!
那個男人是誰
- His name! - What is his name?
那好吧
Who might he be?
執士
Very well.
太太，如果你不說出他的名字
Beadle!
你必須在胸前掛上
Mistress, if you do not speak out
這個罪惡的通姦的標記
his name, wear upon your bodice
這是最後一次
this symbol of your sinful fornication.
警告
Heed not this
你今天起你將成為一個賤民
final warning,
被這個鎮子上的每個男人 女人，和孩子
and you will be a pariah,
驅逐，隔離和斥責
cut off, shunned and reviled by every man,
你們等什麼 掛上吧
woman and child in this town!
它代表的不是我的恥辱而是你們的
Why do you wait? Put it on!
你想幹什麼
It is not a badge of my shame, but your own!
難道我變了很多嗎，親愛的
What do you want?
甚至在我死而復生之後你還要殺死我
Have I changed so much, my beloved,
羅傑？
that you would slay me as I resurrect myself from the dead?
海絲特.
Roger?
難道我對你不夠好嗎？
Hester.
難道我不愛你嗎？
Was I ever unkind to you?
難道我不是把你置於所有女人之上？
Did I not love thee?
神聖的誓言沒有把你交給我？
Did I not see thee above all womanhood?
還是這塊新土地把你變成了異教徒？
Are you not bound to me by sacred oath?
躺到我們的床上，我的妻子
Or has this new land turned thee into a heathen?
為你的罪禱告吧，海絲特·白蘭因.
Lay our bed will thou, wife.
祈求上帝寬恕你的不忠
Pray for thy sins, Hester Prynne.
祈禱，我會把你洗得潔白如雪
Beg the Lord to forgive thy corruption.
是的親愛的，潔白如雪
Pray and I'll wash thee as white as snow.
潔白如雪
White as snow, my love.
White as snow.
阿瑟?
海絲特?
Arthur?
感謝上帝你在這兒
Hester?
- 為什麼要冒這個險 - 我給你報警
Thank God you're here!
我丈夫，羅傑，他還活著
- Why are you taking this risk? - I had to warn you.
啊，親愛的上帝
My husband is alive.
他還活著？
Dear God!
我們肯定會被絞死
Alive?
他為什麼會在此刻現身 難道他是上帝派來
Now we'll hang for certain.
懲罰我們的黑暗使者
Why would he show up at this moment if he wasn't God's dark messenger,
阿瑟，你必須離開這兒
sent to punish us.
我不忍心看到你生活在他
Arthur, you must leave without us.
警惕的目光之下
I cannot bear to see you trapped here,
海絲特，我不能離開 我必須留下來照看你和珠兒
under his watchful eye forever.
不，你不瞭解他
Hester, I must stay and watch over you and Pearl.
他會等我們出賣對方
No. You don't know him.
哪怕是一個輕柔的眼神或是細微的手勢
He'll wait for us to betray each other
求你了，你必須走
with the slightest glance or the merest gesture.
這是上帝的懲罰
Please. You must go!
因為我們曾想擺脫他的意旨
This God's punishment,
我不會離開你的，海絲特.
because we tried to run from His Will.
但願上帝與你同在
I will not say farewell, Hester.
我也與你同在
Pray God watch over you.
每晚替我親吻珠兒
And so will I.
容易看出一部分像媽媽
Kiss Pearl for me each night.
不知道是不是超越了哲人的研究
'Tis easy to see the mother's part in her.
從這孩子的性格和外貌來看
Is it beyond research, I wonder,
大概猜得出她的父親是誰
to analyze her nature, and from it's make and mold,
你有什麼打算，先生
give a shrewd guess as to the father?
哦，親愛的 我不指望你能很快回心轉意
What are your expectations?
但我希望總有一天 你會重新把我
I do not expect your heart to return to you quickly.
放進你的心裏
But I hope one day you will draw me again
愛讓我把心向另一個人敞開
into your heart.
別亂說話，太太
Love has forced me to open my heart to another.
那個教你說這些話的影子情人
Watch your tongue, woman!
他在哪兒？
'Tis this phantom lover who puts these words into your mouth1
他嘴角的溫潤
Where is he?
仍然停留在你的嘴唇 或者是你的胸前
Is his kiss
- 我想知道 - 我坐了六個月冰冷的牢房
still wet on your lips, on your breast?
也沒有告訴那些人
- I demand to know! - If I spent 6 months in a cold jail,
你憑什麼認為我會跟你說
and did not tell these iron men,
這些審判讓我更堅強了，先生
what makes you think I'll tell you now?
我不再是你剛娶的那個小姑娘了
These trials have made me strong!
你為什麼不馬上公開宣佈把我休掉
And I am not the child you married!
不，不
Why not announce yourself openly and cast me off at once.
我不想對你報復，孩子
No, no.
可拆散我們的人還活著
I seek no vengeance against you.
他的外衣上沒有一個
But the man lives who wronged us both.
揭露他醜行的字
He bears no letter of infamy
可我能夠看到他心上的字
wrought into his garment.
敢把我的真實身份透露給他一個字
But I shall read it on his heart.
你們就會被絞死
Breathe one word to him of my true identity,
如果你們愚蠢地想逃走
and you will both hang.
那你們很快就會被發現的
If you try to escape,
很好
you will be easily found.
從野蠻人那裏
Easily!
我學會了耐心
From the savages
海絲特·白蘭因.
I have learned patience,
古蒂·高德威克，謝謝
Hester Prynne.
丁梅斯黛爾牧師牧師 允許我來介紹一位新房客
Goody Gotwick, thank you.
奇林
Reverend, allow me to introduce our newest boarder,
- 奇林·沃爾斯 - 奇林·沃爾斯
Doctor Chilling...
你好，牧師
- Chillingworth. - Chillingworth.
你好，先生.
Good day, man.
為什麼要來我們的殖民地，先生
Good day, sir.
我是醫生，先生 我可以為大家
What brings you to our colony, sir?
祛除疾病
I'm a physician, sir. I would cleanse the ills
我說的有什麼不對嗎？
of the community.
不
Have I said something strange?
只是我很好奇
No.
我們一直祈求一位醫術高明的醫生
I'm amazed.
我看你正把聖經譯成阿爾岡昆語
We have prayed for a skilled physician.
那是最難懂的一種語言
I see you are translating the Bible into Algonquin.
我希望能夠幫上忙，丁梅斯黛爾牧師
A most difficult tongue to master.
我的阿爾岡昆語很流利
If I can be of help, Reverend.
- 流利？ - 是的
I am fluent in Algonquin.
哦，是的，我做過塔蘭泰人的俘虜
- Fluent? - Yes.
只要我說的不對，他們就打我
I was a prisoner of the Tarrantine.
所以我學得突飛猛進
When I spoke improperly, I was whipped.
你是怎麼被抓住的
I learned quite rapidly.
我在弗吉尼亞農場工作的時候 他們來了
How were you captured?
殺了我的妻子愛萊諾 願她的靈魂安息
I was working my farm in Virginia. They came,
和我尚未長大的兒子
killed my wife, Eleanor, God rest her soul,
然後把我作為俘虜賣掉
and our infant son,
很奇怪你並沒有過多的
and sold me into captivity.
痛苦和失望
It's a wonder you're not consumed
不，不，說實話，先生 我欠印弟安人的債
with bitterness and despair.
有人說他們是野蠻人 可我發現真正的野蠻人
No, no. In truth, I am indebted to the Indians.
卻在別的地方
Some say they are savages, but true savagery,
羅傑·白蘭因太太
I find resides elsewhere.
白蘭因太太.
Mistress Roger Prynne.
職責，孩子
Mistress Prynne.
你的職責是什麼，孩子
跟著你去每一個公共場所，太太
And what is your duty, boy?
很好，至少他們會給我讓路
Follow you around, Mistress.
滾回去，賤人
Well, at least they'll make a path for me.
上帝會懲罰你的，罪人
Whore!
賤人
God will punish you, sinner!
你在這兒不受歡迎
Jezebel!
走吧，海絲特·白蘭因!
You're not welcome here!
我要買肥皂，給我三塊
Be gone, Hester Prynne!
雖然我父親身上沒掛著紅字
Soap, please. Three pieces.
可他自己的紅字就印在他的靈魂上
Although he wore no outward symbol ofhis shame,
分離的痛苦影響了大家.
my father wore his own scarlet letteron the bosom ofhis soul.
我是一個非常難纏的孩子
The pain of their separation must have affected us all.
為解相思之苦
I was a troublesome child.
父親帶著約翰尼去野外以求擺脫孤獨
My father ached formy mother,
他們想在英國人和印第安人之間
and filled his loneliness in the wilds with Johnny.
架起一座橋樑
They struggled
並且努力維護著這個夢想
to keep alive their  dream
約翰尼
of building a bridge between English and Indian.
他們離鎮子為什麼這麼近
Johnny,
他們說，我們的人都睡了
why are they so close to town?
所以他們必須保持清醒
They say our people have fallen asleep.
我很擔心
So they must remain awake for all of us.
會有戰爭嗎，阿瑟
I'm worried.
偉大的夢想破滅了，是嗎？
Is war coming?
他說的對
The great experiment is not working, is it?
如果真的有戰爭 如何阻止那些皈依的印第安人叛變
Yes, he's right.
趁著我們睡覺的時候
If there's war, what is to stop our praying Indians
割斷我們的喉嚨
from rising up
信念，托馬斯，信念
and slitting our throats as we sleep?
我知道什麼能阻止他們
Faith, Thomas. Faith.
阿瑟與約翰尼的友誼
I know what will stop them.
約翰尼絕不會背叛阿瑟
Arthur's friendship with Johnny Sassamon.
他崇拜阿瑟
Johnny would never betray Arthur.
就像彼特崇拜
He worships him.
耶穌
As Peter worshipped
先生們，醫生
Jesus.
如果真的有戰爭
Gentlemen. Doctor.
就請求上帝吧
If there's a true war,
我們和野蠻人都活不了
God help us all.
我看總督對徵兆的判斷力比不上他
for neither we nor the savaged will survive it.
他的虔誠的顧問.
I see the governor appreciates the signs less than yee,
不會事事如意
his Godly advisors.
很奇怪，弗吉尼亞也是如此
It is not always easy.
在他們攻擊之前
Strangely, the same thing happened in Virginia.
根本沒有任何徵兆
Before the attack,
什麼樣的徵兆？
there were signs that went unheeded.
寒冷的冬天，糧食欠收
What manner of signs?
鎮子裏有過多的信徒和外來人
The bad winter. The crop failures.
一些小小的不安分子
Far too many Quakers and foreigners in the town.
諸如此類
Some minor elements
說的對，說的對
of witchcraft, etc.
我們的第一個徵兆是
Exactly!
海絲特·白蘭因和她的那些聚會
Our first sign was that
然後又是嚴寒的冬天
of Hester Prynne and her women's meetings.
糧食欠收
Then the severe winter.
您看，先生
The failed crops.
我的同事從一開始
You see, sir,
就擔心白蘭因太太的事
my colleague has feared from the start,
跟巫術有關係
that in the matter of Mistress Prynne,
為什麼一直以來你們沒有採取適當的措施
witchcraft was involved.
清潔殖民地？
Then why in all this time have you not taken measures
您的意思是？
to cleanse your colony?
你們查過那些參加聚會的女人嗎？
What measures do you speak of?
有沒有詢問過接生的人
Did you examine the women present at those meetings?
或者檢查過那個孩子有沒有女巫的標記
Have you queried the midwife,
雖然我要穿越死亡陰影之地
or inspected the child for the witch's marks?
可我不怕邪惡
因為有您存在，有您權杖的指引，有您給我安慰
I shall fear no evil.
您讓我的敵人與我坐在同一張桌前
您為我施塗油之禮
I prepare us a table in the presence of thine enemy.
My cup
您無盡的仁慈和憐憫會與我同行
runneth over.
而我將永遠做您的僕人
Surely goodness
and mercy shall follow me.
孩子很乾淨
I will dwell in the house of the Lord.
到目前為止
The babe's clean,
海絲特太太,
at present.
我們會把孩子暫時留給你
Hester,
可你要保證她會成為基督信徒
we shall leave your child with you for the present,
是的，是的
but you must assure us it will be raised a Christian.
我會的
Yes, yes.
今天我是你的朋友，孩子
Yes.
但是不可能天天如此，不
I've been your friend today.
因為我心中的仇恨，與日俱增
But it cannot always be so. No.
我是那麼地渴望你
For inside me I grow more wretched by the day.
我怕我會因為你
I yearn so much for thee.
把整個世界毀掉
I fear I might destroy
告訴老哈里森 什麼事讓你心煩
her whole world to win her back.
我真沒有想到
Tell old Harriet what's troubling you.
他們的懲罰會這樣殘忍和狡詐
I never imagined
斯頓赫爾和奇夫在大街上為我敲鑼打鼓
how cruel and cunning their punishment could be.
鎮上的人對我指點，漫罵
Stonehall y Cheever stop to preach at me in the street.
甚至還有孩子
The people pointing and shouting.
那個可惡的小鼓手跟著我到處走
Even the children.
也許這也是徒勞的
And that horrible drummer boy following me everywhere.
我作為女人不能過快樂的一生
Perhaps it was all for naught.
活著還有什麼意思
I wonder if to be a woman is worthwhile at all.
勇敢點，孩子
Even for the happiest of women.
至少你知道了什麼是愛
Courage, child.
難道愛的代價是要讓我毀掉他嗎
Take heart. At least you've known what it is to love.
難道
But what if I've repaid it by destroying him?
我一直堅信的一切都是虛假的
What if
愚蠢
everything I believed so strongly was a lie?
而自私的
Vain and
白蘭因殘忍的懲罰
selfish.
還在繼續著
Prynne's cruelpunishments
季節交替
were succeeding.
而父親與母親之間的距離無法穿越
The seasons ran theircourse.
母親冒著極大的危險給父親寫信
The distance between them was impassable.
提醒他堅守他們的愛情，堅守沉默
My mother took the terrible risk ofwriting to my father,
而白蘭因若有若無
reminding to keep theirlove and his silence.
接連不斷地出現
The subtle but constant presence ofPrynne
折磨著我父親的心靈
was a torment
至於白蘭因
that threatened my father's very soul.
他報復的慾望
As forPrynne,
開始膨脹
his lust forrevenge
他更加變本加厲地報復
fed on itself
你好，米杜芭
so that he hungered formore.
今天真是個出門的好天氣
Good morrow, Mituba.
可憐的米杜芭
What a pleasant day for a ride.
你對太太的忠誠是出了名的，現在我知道原因了
Poor Mituba.
你那乾巴巴的午餐是她情人的信嗎
You're renowned for your loyalty to your Mistress, and I see why.
你知道，我有能力把你當成通姦者的同謀抓起來
Was your dry lunch a communication from her lover?
把你帶到官員面前問話
I have the power to arrest you as an accomplice t adultery
不過你是個奴隸
and bring you before the magistrates for questioning.
他們可能會用鞭子把你打死
And since you are a slave,
打死，打死
they might whip you to death.
我只想幫助我們都愛的那個人
Easy. Easy.
從撒旦的魔爪下逃出來
I only want to help the one we both love.
哦，我的上帝，夠了
To free herself from the grasp of a fiend.
他是不是當著你的面脫光
Dear Lord, this is it!
全部脫光
He made you strip naked before him!
當時屋裏有人嗎
Totally naked!
好好想想，想想
Was there a presence in the room?
也許他是帶著偽裝進來的
Now think! Think!
他是不是變成了一隻鳥，
He might have come in one of his many disguises.
哦，上帝，我感覺到了
Did he come as a bird?
魔鬼的存在
Oh, God. I feel
救救你自己吧 不然就太晚了
the presence of Lucifer!
先生們
Save yourself before it's too late!
夠了，夠了
Gentlemen, please!
夠了
Enough!
回去吧，米杜芭 你幫了很大的忙
向你的主人誇誇我們
Go home, Mituba. You've been a wondrous help.
回家吧
Commend us to your Mistress.
Go home.
這麼說，這兒有個惡魔
需要剷除
So there is a malignancy
但是，一個奴隸上法庭能做什麼證
to be cut our here.
那隻鳥，顯然是哈里森·希本斯
But what kind of witness will a slave be in court?
怎麼了，珠兒
The bird, obviously. is Harriet Hibbons.
- 原諒我，海絲特. - 哈里森
What is it, Pearl?
我藏在你這兒應該是最安全的了
- Forgive me, Hester. - Harriet.
怎麼了
Yours was the first place I thought of to hide.
他們，他們，
What is it?
闖進了我們屋子 現在應該去樹林裏找我了
They've, they've, they've ah...
我被說成是個
broken into my house. They're looking for me in the woods.
女巫
I've been named
哦，上帝
as a witch!
停下
In the name of God!
是，長官
Halt there!
你們闖進我家幹什麼，少校
Yes, sir!
讓開，夫人
What's the meaning of this intrusion?
我們知道那個女巫在這兒
Stand aside, woman!
這裏沒有外人
We know the witch is in here.
只有我，我的孩子和米杜芭
There's no one inside
要是你沒有搜查令，請走吧
but me, my child and Mituba.
丁梅斯黛爾牧師
So unless you have a warrant, be gone.
怎麼回事，少校
Reverend Dimmesdale.
我們圍住了一個女巫
What's happening, major?
在海絲特·白蘭因的屋子裏
We've cornered ourselves a witch.
如果這個房子裏真的有女巫的話，少校
Here in Hester Prynne's cottage.
我會找到的
If there's a witch inside the house, major,
好吧
I'll find her.
士兵，守住門口
Right.
是的
One man at the door.
珠兒長高了
- Soldier! - Sir?
她是個淘氣包
Pearl's grown tall.
很任性
She's an elf.
感謝上帝
Willful.
這麼久了
Dear God, Hester.
你瘦了
It's been so long.
你藏了什麼了嗎，海絲特?
You'r thin.
為什麼
Are you hiding someone, Hester?
你為什麼要冒這個險
Why do you...?
去激怒那些人
Why are you risking
因為她不是女巫 除了說實話
further anger from the elders?
她沒有犯過罪
Because she is no witch! She's committed no crime
如果她是無罪的
beyond speaking her mind!
我向你保證她不會受到傷害
If she is innocent,
阿瑟，發生了這麼多事
I assure you no harm will befall her.
你怎麼還能相信那些殘忍的人
Arthur. After all that has happened,
難道你沒看見嗎
how can you still trust these iron men?
上個月他們帶莎麗·肖特去問話
Don't you see what's happening?
他們關了她兩天 上個星期是瑪麗·盧林斯
Last month they brought Sally Short for questioning.
海絲特，他們只是詢問她們
They held her for 2 days. Last week it was Mary Rollins.
這有什麼罪
They just questioned them!
罪行是她們什麼都沒有做
What's the crime in that?
你看不出
The crime is they had nothing!
這是一個惡毒陰謀的一部分嗎
Don't you see
- 你是怎麼了 - 天啊，夫人
this is some malevolence?
你還想怎麼樣
- What has become of you? - God, woman!
為了你我放棄所有神聖的東西
What are your demands?
我進了地獄
I've given up everything I own sacred!
你的丈夫，日夜周旋在我的身邊
I'm in Hell!
而鎮上的居民都來找我釋放他們的心靈的負擔
In the eye of your husband, who lurks at my side day and night.
我是骯髒的
In the eye of all who come to me to unburden their soul!
我是騙子
I'm a pollution!
不，他們才是骯髒的
I'm a lie!
他們才是騙子
They are the pollution!
而你在縱容他們毀掉你身上美好的東西
They are the lie!
我愛的那個人怎麼了
But you allow them to destroy all that is good in you!
他還活在你的身體裏嗎
What's happened to the man I love?
我們的愛，夫人，是荒唐的
Does he not still live inside thee?
我們心聲也是假的
Our love, woman, was a folly.
而我們因此受到了懲罰
And the voice we heard,
我變成什麼了
we have been punished for listening to!
他們出賣了世界上唯一向她表現出好意的人
What have I become?
還有什麼比這更糟糕的
To betray the onlyperson on earth who had shown herkindness.
米杜芭？
What could feel worse than that?
可憐的米杜芭
Mituba?
當白蘭因傳喚她的時候
Poor, mute Mituba.
她只是想消除可能給女主人帶來的傷害
When Prynne summoned her,
大家肅靜
she wanted only to undo the harm sh'd caused her Mistress.
肅靜，我說肅靜
Peace in this House!
你覺得這些程序很好笑嗎，太太
Peace, I say. Peace!
你指望我把它們當回事嗎
You find these proceedings humorous, Mistress?
看著一群成年人揭開我的隱私
Do you expect me to take them seriously?
尋找女巫的標記不好笑嗎
You're a bunch of grown men
那個奴隸，米杜芭
poking around my private parts looking for witch's marks!
肅靜，肅靜
The slave, Mituba...
恐怕我們的證人，那個奴隸，米杜芭 已經死了
Peace, I say. Peace!
我說過她是個女巫
The witness, the slave Mituba, has been found dead.
- 希本斯太太是個女巫 - 她是個女巫
I told you she was a witch!
女巫
- Mistress Hibbons is a witch! - She's a witch!
你們都失去理智了嗎
Witch!
這裏沒有什麼女巫
Have you lost all reason?
這是謀殺
There's no witchcraft here!
警衛
This is murder!
制止這個女人
Guards,
撒旦從來不附著在女人的身上
restrain this woman!
如果他在這兒，也許就附著在你們男人的身上
Satan is not at work here among the women!
是撒旦在講話
But if he's here, perhaps is at work among you men!
總督
Here Satan speaks!
我有證據呈遞
Governor?
你們都知道
I have evidence to render.
希本斯夫人曾經替白蘭因太太接生
As you know,
那個珠兒
Mistress Hibbons midwifed Mistress Prynne's
可愛的珠兒
baby Pearl.
雜種
Sweet Pearl.
不
Bastard!
珠兒，珠兒，可愛的珠兒
No!
多希望你是我的女兒
Pearl.
可憐的沒父親的孩子
I wish you were my girl.
你想玩個遊戲嗎
Poor fatherless child.
好的，照我這樣做
Would you like to learn a game?
如果我捏我的鼻子
Yes. Now do what I do.
該你了 很好，很好
If I pinch my nose.
現在
You too. Very good, very good.
我掀開我的衣服露出我的肚子
Now,
現在讓我看看你的肚子
pull up my shirt and show my tummy tum-tum.
掀開你的衣服
Now show me your tummy tum-tum.
這就是女巫的標誌
Pull up your shirt.
這就是惡魔的孩子
Behold the witch's mark!
這就是惡魔的孩子 這個孩子應該被絞死
Behold the devil's own child!
不
The devil's own child! The devil's own child!
把孩子給我
希本斯是無辜的，不能絞死她
無辜？從你第一次為那個女人求情
This woman is innocent!
我們以主的名義夢想和奮鬥的一切就受到了威脅
Innocent? Since you first spoke of this woman,
我已經聽夠了
all we've dreames and toiled for in God's name has been threatened!
你聽見了嗎？
I've heard enough!
爭論！辯解！分歧！
Have you listened?
這都是撒旦在做祟
Factions! Arguments! Dissent!
現在鎮子亂成一團
That is the work of Satan!
我父親冒險最後一次去見我母親
The town was in an uproar.
告訴她如果他們要絞死哈里森
My fatherrisked one last meeting with my mother,
那過不了多久
convinced that ifthey were to hang
母親和我也會被抓起來 然後被絞死
Harriet, it would not be long
我要大聲喊叫
before my motherand I would be seized... and hung.
我無法控制自己
I had to speak out.
詛咒你的丈夫吧，海絲特
I couldn't stop myself.
你和珠兒必須躲起來 今晚
Damn your husband!
我不能
You and Pearl must go in hiding. Tonight.
我不能走
I cannot.
你在說什麼
I cannot run.
請原諒我
What are you saying?
無論發生什麼
Forgive me.
向我保證你會永遠照顧珠兒
Whatever happens,
上帝，這種痛苦你還要承受多久
promise me you'll look after Pearl. I.
只要有勇氣我就會去接受
God, woman, how much further must you take this?
如果哈里森被絞死 我會陪她一起死
As far as my strength will take me.
我會讓其他女人和我們同一陣線
If Harriet is to hang, I must hang with her.
他們不能把我們都絞死
I'll ask the other women to stand with us.
海絲特，我們永遠不能在一起了嗎
They can't hang us all.
我愛你
Hester, are we ever to know a life together?
哦上帝啊，我愛你，永遠都愛你
I love thee.
我也會永遠愛你
I love thee and always will.
上帝啊 我們曾毫無保留地站在你面前
I will always love thee.
現在作為一家人
Lord God, we stood before thee naked once,
我們再次毫無保留地站在你面前
and now we stand before thee
上帝，既然你把這個禮物送給了我
naked again, as a family.
我就絕不，絕不放棄它
God! Thou has given me this as a gift,
只要我還有勇氣
and I will not give it up!
阿瑟?
Not while I have the strength.
Arthur?
阿瑟?
晚上好，白蘭因太太. 在等什麼人嗎？
Arthur?
哦，不
Evening Mistress Prynne. Expecting someone else?
你剛才不是在叫阿瑟嗎
Ah, no.
據我所知，只有一個阿瑟 那就是丁梅斯黛爾
Didn't you call out for Arthur?
你誤解我了 我沒有…
The only Arthur I know is... Dimmesdale.
我早就該猜到
You misunderstood me, I didn't say...
你這個淘氣的姑娘
I should have guessed long ago.
你勾引了我們的牧師
You naughty girl.
上帝啊我的聖父，我該如何品味這無價的佳餚呢
So you fucked our minister.
沒想到，他對你做了什麼
God, I'm about to savour a priceless morsel!
他親吻你的胸部？
Up we go!
他舔舐你了嗎？
Did he suck your breasts?
他舔舐你什麼地方
Did he lick you?
讓我看看
Where did he lick you?
上帝啊，我多希望進入你的身體
Show me!
這就是你讓我對你產生幻想的代價
How I wanted to put it in you!
你迷惑我
This is to make you pay for my fantasies.
可你卻把身體給了另一個人
While you were torturing me,
該死的女巫！
you were giving it to another.
滾出去！
Damned witch!
穿上你的褲子滾出去！
Get out!
你這雜種！滾出去！
Do up your britches and get out!
我會很高興看到你和你的牧師被絞死
Bastard! Get out of here!
開門，醫生
How I will enjoy watching you and the pastor hang!
你和我之間的問題必須馬上解決
Open up, doctor!
好吧，阿瑟·丁梅斯黛爾
There are matters between us we must discus immediately.
這是天意
So, Arthur Dimmesdale.
他被謀殺了！
At last justice is done!
快去找民兵 快去找警衛
？a sido asesinado!
這是神跡 上帝給了我們神跡
Call out the militia! Call out the guards!
肯定是印第安人幹的,把他們關起來
It's a sign! The Lord has sent us a sign!
我們偏離了上帝
看他怎麼懲罰我們吧
We have strayed!
是布魯斯特，那些野蠻人
See how he punishes us!
把他給殺了
It's Brewster. Those savages
我的兒子！我的兒子！
have killed him!
該死的異教徒！
My son! My son!
在他們把我們謀殺在床上之前
Damned heathens!
把那些印第安人關起來
Lock up the praying Indians,
把他們關起來
before they murder us in our beds!
把印第安人關進籬笆院子裏
Get the praying Indians!
快點
Praying Indians into the compound!
我們忠誠於你們
We are loyal to you!
白蘭因太太 受馬賽諸賽海岸殖民地總督之命
因為你的種種異端行為 你被逮捕了
By order of the Governor of the Massachusetts Bay Colony,
住手！是我們的人殺了布魯斯特！
you are under arrest for the crime of heresy.
是我們的人，我有證據
Stop this. It was one of us who killed Brewster.
雜種！
I have proof.
約翰尼，麥特坎姆在河邊，我看見他了
Bastard!
告訴他快來拯救他的人，快去
Johnny, run to Metacomet's place by the river.
女巫們來了
Tell him to come and save his people. Run, man!
打開囚籠
Here come the witches!
- 別管孩子 - 珠兒!
Open the cell.
- 進去，進去你這個女人 - 珠兒?
- Never mind the child. - Pearl!
別擔心，白蘭因太太
- Get in, woman! - Pearl?
- 我會把她養大，讓她敬畏上帝 - 珠兒
Worry not, Mistress.
如果這是為了最高利益
I'll see she's raised up to fear the Lord.
我們將服從您的旨意
開門，殺人犯
他們說的是真的
Open up, murderer!
大家別那樣做
這裏根本沒有什麼女巫
絞死她
There is no witchcraft here!
如果我們絞死這些女人
那我們變成了什麼
If we hang these women,
我們是誰
then what have we become?
又怎麼能代表上帝
Who are we
來執法
to condemn
我深愛這個女人
on God's behalf?
我就是
I love this woman.
她孩子的父親
I am
在上帝的眼裏
the father of her child.
我就是她的丈夫
And in God's eyes,
- 絞死她 - 絞死她
I am her husband.
現在如果你們一定要絞死一個人
才能消除
If you must hang someone,
你們的憤怒和恐懼
to appease
那就絞死我吧
your anger and fear,
絞死他！
then hang me.
絞死他！絞死他！
Hang him!
絞死他！
Hang him! Hang him!
Hang him!
絞死他！
雜種！
- 珠兒在哪 - 她在兵工廠
Bastards!
快走
海絲特
Hester!
我的女兒在哪？
她在會議室裏
Where's my daughter, Pearl?
你們自由了，我的朋友 回麥特坎姆那兒去吧
She's in the meeting house!
回森林裏去
You are free, my people. Go back to Metacomet!
我們走，帶上我們的人民
Go back to the forest!
貝靈漢總督會想方設法 向英國政府隱瞞這件事
他向我保證會為你摘下紅字
Bellingham will do anything to conceal this madness from England.
並且公開向你道歉
He has sworn to me that he will remove the letter.
愛和恨的距離有多遠
And make thee a public apology.
以後我們再也不受對方的束縛了
How close they are, love and hate.
安息吧，羅傑·白蘭因
We're no less bound by one than the other.
這紅字達到了一個目的
Rest in peace, Roger Prynne.
雖然並不是
This letter has served a purpose.
他們的初衷
Though not the one
我為什麼還要留在這兒
they had intended.
讓他們接受我？被他們馴服我？
So why would I stay here?
- 沒有完美的世界，海絲特 - 對，沒有完美
To be accepted by them? To be tamed by them?
所以我們要建立一個親世界
- There is no perfect world. - No, not perfect.
而且為了珠兒
But we came here to make a new one.
我必須離開這兒
And for Pearl's sake,
海絲特
I must do just that.
Hester.
看著我
Hester!
如果看著你，我就無法離開
Look at me.
那就走吧
If I look at you, I won't be able to leave
勇敢地面對外界
Then leave.
不過海絲特
Brave the wilds!
我不會讓你丟下我一個人走
But Hester,
他們在看我們
I'm not letting you go without me.
在遙遠的卡羅萊納
They're watching us.
我的父母終於找到了
In the faraway Carolinas,
他們久違了的幸福
they were at last to find a measure ofthe happiness
在我不到十歲的時候父親去世了
that hade been denied them forso long.
有人說，那裏對他的懲罰
My fatherdied before I reached my teens.
我的母親沒有再愛上其他人
Some say that was a punishment.
有人說，那也是對她的一種懲罰
My motherneverremarried norloved another.
可是我認為
Some say that was a punishment.
這不是懲罰
As forme,
我的父母分享了他人所沒有的愛
I do not see it that way.
我知道那愛的精神就存在於我的心裏
Myparents shared a love like no other.
並且永遠存在於我的孩子們心裏
I know the spirit ofthat love lives within me.
誰能說清，在上帝的眼中，什麼是罪惡呢
And will live within my children forever.
Who is to say what is a sin in God's eyes?